<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>DevOps on Tech Fuse News</title><link>https://mer0x.github.io/techfuse/tags/devops/</link><description>Recent content in DevOps on Tech Fuse News</description><generator>Hugo -- 0.145.0</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 16:11:13 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mer0x.github.io/techfuse/tags/devops/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to deploying Kubernetes on bare-metal</title><link>https://mer0x.github.io/techfuse/posts/how-to-deploying-kubernetes-on-bare-metal/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 16:11:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mer0x.github.io/techfuse/posts/how-to-deploying-kubernetes-on-bare-metal/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="how-to-deploy-kubernetes-on-bare-metal-a-detailed-technical-tutorial">How to Deploy Kubernetes on Bare-Metal: A Detailed Technical Tutorial&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Kubernetes has become a cornerstone for managing containerized applications in production environments. Although cloud platforms like AWS, Google Cloud, and Azure provide powerful managed Kubernetes services, a growing number of organizations are opting to deploy Kubernetes on bare-metal servers. This approach offers increased control, improved performance, and potentially lower costs due to minimized dependencies on cloud vendors. In this comprehensive guide, we will walk through the steps to successfully deploy Kubernetes on bare-metal servers.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to self-host nextcloud securely</title><link>https://mer0x.github.io/techfuse/posts/how-to-self-host-nextcloud-securely/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 16:02:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mer0x.github.io/techfuse/posts/how-to-self-host-nextcloud-securely/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Self-hosting Nextcloud offers a personal or organizational solution to manage and share files, calendars, contacts, and more. By taking control of sensitive data, you avoid third-party cloud storage risks, ensuring compliance with data protection regulations. Nextcloud offers extensive features and is supported by a vibrant community making it an ideal choice for self-hosting. This tutorial will guide you through securely self-hosting Nextcloud using Docker, leveraging tools like Nginx for web servers, Let&amp;rsquo;s Encrypt for free SSL/TLS certificates, and fail2ban for intrusion prevention.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to homelab automation with Ansible</title><link>https://mer0x.github.io/techfuse/posts/2025-02-28-how-to-homelab-automation-with-ansible/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mer0x.github.io/techfuse/posts/2025-02-28-how-to-homelab-automation-with-ansible/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="how-to-homelab-automation-with-ansible-a-comprehensive-guide">How to Homelab Automation with Ansible: A Comprehensive Guide&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In today&amp;rsquo;s rapidly evolving tech landscape, automation has become a cornerstone of efficient IT infrastructure management. Self-hosted homelabs allow tech enthusiasts and IT professionals to create, experiment, and manage their environments without involving third-party services. Using Ansible, a powerful automation tool, you can streamline processes, minimize manual intervention, and cultivate consistency within your self-hosted projects.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ansible is a versatile tool renowned for its simplicity, agentless architecture, and wide range of integrations, making it a favorite for managing complex environments. In this tutorial, we&amp;rsquo;ll delve into the world of homelab automation using Ansible. We&amp;rsquo;ll cover practical, real-world examples and offer insights into integrating with tools like Docker, Proxmox, and Cloudflare to enhance your homelab operations.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to Proxmox vs ESXi</title><link>https://mer0x.github.io/techfuse/posts/2025-02-28-how-to-proxmox-vs-esxi/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mer0x.github.io/techfuse/posts/2025-02-28-how-to-proxmox-vs-esxi/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Choosing the right virtualization platform is crucial for successfully self-hosting your applications and services. Two of the most popular platforms for virtualization are &lt;strong>Proxmox Virtual Environment (Proxmox VE)&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>VMware ESXi&lt;/strong>. Both have their strengths, and their suitability largely depends on the specific needs of the user or organization.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Proxmox&lt;/strong> is known for its open-source foundation, full feature set, and active community support, making it ideal for those with a penchant for flexible and cost-effective solutions. &lt;strong>ESXi&lt;/strong>, part of VMware&amp;rsquo;s vSphere suite, is renowned for its stable performance, extensive enterprise features, and robust customer support.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to running AI models locally with Ollama</title><link>https://mer0x.github.io/techfuse/posts/2025-02-28-how-to-running-ai-models-locally-with-ollama/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mer0x.github.io/techfuse/posts/2025-02-28-how-to-running-ai-models-locally-with-ollama/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="how-to-run-ai-models-locally-with-ollama">How to Run AI Models Locally with Ollama&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In the rapidly advancing world of artificial intelligence, running AI models locally is an emerging trend, giving enthusiasts and developers the power to harness AI without relying solely on cloud services. This approach provides greater control over data, security, and customization. Ollama is a robust tool designed for running AI models locally. By enabling AI model deployment within a self-controlled environment, Ollama caters to organizations and individuals seeking to integrate AI capabilities securely and efficiently.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to self-hosted password manager (Vaultwarden)</title><link>https://mer0x.github.io/techfuse/posts/2025-02-28-how-to-self-hosted-password-manager-vaultwarden/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mer0x.github.io/techfuse/posts/2025-02-28-how-to-self-hosted-password-manager-vaultwarden/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="how-to-self-host-password-manager-vaultwarden">How to Self-Host Password Manager (Vaultwarden)&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Password management is a fundamental aspect of modern digital security. Choosing to self-host a password manager can significantly enhance your security and give you full control over your data. Vaultwarden, formerly known as Bitwarden_RS, is a lightweight, self-hostable version of Bitwarden—one of the most popular open-source password managers. In this tutorial, we will guide you through setting up your instance of Vaultwarden using Docker and other popular tools like Proxmox, Ansible, and Cloudflare to fortify your password management infrastructure.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to self-hosted VPN (WireGuard/OpenVPN)</title><link>https://mer0x.github.io/techfuse/posts/2025-02-28-how-to-self-hosted-vpn-wireguardopenvpn/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mer0x.github.io/techfuse/posts/2025-02-28-how-to-self-hosted-vpn-wireguardopenvpn/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="how-to-self-host-a-vpn-using-wireguardopenvpn">How to Self-Host a VPN Using WireGuard/OpenVPN&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In today&amp;rsquo;s digital age, privacy and secure access to networks are more important than ever. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re looking to protect your online activities, access geographically restricted content, or securely connect to your home network while away, setting up your own VPN can be an excellent solution. With the rise of services like WireGuard and OpenVPN, self-hosting a VPN is both accessible and highly effective.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to Set Up Docker Networking</title><link>https://mer0x.github.io/techfuse/posts/2025-02-28-how-to-set-up-docker-networking/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mer0x.github.io/techfuse/posts/2025-02-28-how-to-set-up-docker-networking/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In this tutorial, we will delve into the intricacies of setting up Docker networking specifically tailored for scalable applications. Docker, a powerful platform for developing, shipping, and running applications inside portable containers, also provides robust networking features. We&amp;rsquo;ll explore how to effectively implement Docker networking to ensure your applications can scale seamlessly and handle increasing loads efficiently.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="prerequisites">Prerequisites&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Before we begin, ensure you have the following:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Docker installed on your system. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t installed Docker yet, you can find installation instructions for various operating systems on the &lt;a href="https://docs.docker.com/get-docker/">Official Docker website&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Basic familiarity with Docker concepts such as containers, Docker Compose, and Dockerfile.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>A simple application (e.g., a web server) already Dockerized, meaning it should have a Dockerfile or a Docker Compose file to define its environmental setup.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="implementation">Implementation&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="step-1-understanding-docker-network-types">Step 1: Understanding Docker Network Types&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Docker provides several network types, but for scalable applications, the main types you should consider are &lt;code>bridge&lt;/code>, &lt;code>overlay&lt;/code>, and &lt;code>macvlan&lt;/code>:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Using GitHub Actions for CI/CD in self-hosted environments</title><link>https://mer0x.github.io/techfuse/posts/2025-02-28-1552-using-github-actions-for-cicd-in-self-hosted-environments/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mer0x.github.io/techfuse/posts/2025-02-28-1552-using-github-actions-for-cicd-in-self-hosted-environments/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="using-github-actions-for-cicd-in-self-hosted-environments">Using GitHub Actions for CI/CD in Self-hosted Environments&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>GitHub Actions is a powerful platform that allows developers to automate tasks within their software development lifecycle. It seamlessly integrates with GitHub repositories, enabling continuous integration and deployment (CI/CD). While GitHub provides cloud-hosted runners, there are scenarios where you might want to use self-hosted runners, such as requiring specific hardware, software configurations, or enhanced control over the execution environment.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this tutorial, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore how to set up GitHub Actions for CI/CD in self-hosted environments, ensuring you leverage its full potential.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Securing your network with pfSense firewall</title><link>https://mer0x.github.io/techfuse/posts/2025-02-28-1557-securing-your-network-with-pfsense-firewall/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mer0x.github.io/techfuse/posts/2025-02-28-1557-securing-your-network-with-pfsense-firewall/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="securing-your-network-with-pfsense-firewall">Securing Your Network with pfSense Firewall&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Securing your network is crucial in today&amp;rsquo;s digital age where cyber threats are increasingly sophisticated. One of the most effective ways to safeguard your network is by implementing a robust firewall. pfSense, an open-source firewall software, offers comprehensive security features, scalability, and reliability, making it an excellent choice for both small and large networks. In this tutorial, we will explore how to secure your network using pfSense, with detailed steps and real-world examples.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>